Dmitry Pershin

☑ dapper1291@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/dapper91

✓ Yekaterinburg, Russian Federation **1** dapper 91. github.io

Software engineer with more than six years of experience working on projects from different fields like cybersecurity, cloud computing, distributed systems, fintech; looking to become a part of an experienced developer team to work on innovative software and services.

Education

Ural State Technical University, M.S.in computer science, faculty of radio engineering, summa cum laude

Experience

Software Engineer at Tochka Bank / 05.2019 - present

skills: rust python sql distributed systems highly-available services rabbitmq postgresql kubernetes

- Fully designed, developed and launched the quick payments service. The quick payments service is a financial infrastructure that allows customers to make payments without cash or plastic cards in near-real-time. It had been implemented from scratch and handled hundreds of thousands of payments a day. The service became profitable in one year after the launch.
- Designed, implemented and configured CI/CD process including unit and integration testing, code analysis, application build and deployment which increased code quality, lowered bugs quantity and reduced delay from commit to deployment to several minutes.

Software Engineer at Yandex / 11.2018 - 05.2019

skills: python mongodb distributed systems highly-available services

- Took part in development of a highly-performant and highly-available task scheduling SAAS platform that provided optimal company cluster resources utilization which reduced the cluster maintenance expenses. The service was able to store and process several terabytes of user data in multiple data centers.
- Took part in development and improvement of service API and SDK providing an ability to describe complex execution pipelines on several thousand of servers in multiple data centers. As a result the service was able to provide availability 99.99%.

Software Engineer at USSC Ltd. / 08.2016 - 11.2018

skills: c++ python networking cybersecurity

- Took part in development of software for industrial networks cybersecurity analysis, malware attacks prevention and network traffic inspection. The product was able to detect cyberattacks on enterprise networks and helped in incident investigation at critical facilities.
- Rewritten some security modules from multi-threaded to asynchronous execution model which **increased soft-ware performance by more than 50%** and made it possible to monitor much more production facilities without hardware update.
- Developed a module that used SCAP (security content automation protocol) standard to analyze OS integrity and protection using open world-wide vulnerability database which let the system to detect security flaws as soon as possible.

Skills

Languages	Databases	Frameworks/Libs	Dev tools	Other	
Rust	PostgreSQL	tokio	Git	Linux	Networking
Python	MongoDB	asyncio	Docker	Kubernetes	Distributed Systems
C/C++	Redis	aiohttp		RabbitMQ	Machine Learning Basics
	Elasticsearch	flask		Kafka	CI/CD
		scikit-learn		SQL	
				BASH	